Marilyn Pearl Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Marilyn Pearl Gallery records
1925-2000, bulk 1976-1993
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Marilyn Pearl Gallery
7.4 linear feet
The records of the Marilyn Pearl Gallery are dated 1925-2000, with the bulk of the ematerial from the period 1976-1993. The collection measures 7.4 linear feet and consists of artists' files, exhibition files, and business records documenting affiliated artists and gallery activities.
Provenance
Marilyn Pearl donated the records of her gallery to the Archives of American Art in 2002.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
The Marilyn Pearl Gallery (est. 1976-circa 1993) was an art gallery in New York, N.Y. specializing American art from the 1920s-1950s.
Marilyn Pearl (Mrs. Alan Loesberg), the daughter and granddaughter of art collectors from Akron and Cleveland, Ohio, as a young child began developing an appreciation for and true love of art. After a stint as a history teacher, Ms. Pearl was determined to establish her own gallery. With help from family, her dream became a reality when the Marilyn Pearl Gallery opened at 29 West 57th Street, New York, in 1976. In 1982, the gallery relocated to 38 East 57th Street, and in 1987 moved to 420 West Broadway in SoHo. Although the gallery closed in the early 1990s, Ms. Pearl continued to operate as a private dealer and expanded her activities to international art fairs, among them the Basel Art Fair.
Among the artists represented by the gallery were: Bernard Chaet, Stephen Greene, Clinton Hill, Pat Lasch, Michael Loew, Winifred Lutz, Jim McShea, Jeanne Miles, Henry Pearson, Pedro Perez, Stephen Robin, Charmion von Wiegand, and Ellen Weiner.
Pearl's first sales were works by sculptor Winifred Lutz, known for site-specific installations. Ms. Lutz remained part of Marilyn Pearl Gallery's stable throughout its history. In addition to emerging artists, Marilyn Pearl also was interested in traditional art forms, and eventually specialized in exhibiting American art from the 1920s-1950s, with particular emphasis on geometric abstraction. In addition, Marilyn Pearl Gallery presented a number of exhibitions exploring WPA era murals, American Abstract Artists, and post-war figurative work. By the 1980s, the gallery's annual schedule usually featured summer shows of new talent; several artists first introduced in this manner developed long-term relationships with Marilyn Pearl Gallery.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Marilyn Pearl Gallery are dated 1925-2000, with the bulk of the ematerial from the period 1976-1993. The collection measures 7.4 linear feet and consists of artists' files, exhibition files, and business records documenting affiliated artists and gallery activities.
Artist files are found for: René Pierre Allain, Bernard Chaet, Stephen Greene, Clinton Hill, Pat Lasch, Michael Loew, Winifred Lutz, Jim McShea, Jeanne Miles, Henry Pearson, Pedro Perez, Stephen Robin, Charmion von Wiegand, and Ellen Weiner. They contain the following types of records in varying combinations: correspondence with the artist, collectors, galleries and museums; printed material including publicity, exhibition catalogs and announcements of Marilyn Pearl Gallery and other venues; photographs; financial records concerning sales and exhibition expenses. In general, items dated prior the gallery's existence and after its closing are printed material relating to the artist. A notable exception is the small number of the personal papers of Charmion von Wiegand that include letters from her husband, writer and editor Joseph Freeman.
Exhibition files are arranged chronologically by exhibition date, 1977, 1980-1992 and consist of correspondence, invoices, printed material, publicity, and photographs.
Business records document the routine affairs of the gallery. Included are client correspondence, inventory cards (work in stock, pieces returned to artists, and works sold), a nearly complete set of invoices for gallery sales for the period 1976-1986, consignment records, appraisals, mailing lists, guest books, and records regarding Basel Art Fairs of 1989-1993.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 3 series:
Series 1: Artists' Files, 1925-2000 (Boxes 1-4; 3.6 linear ft.)
Series 2: Exhibition Files, 1973-1992 (Boxes 4-5; 1.15 linear ft.)
Series 3: Business Records, 1976-2000 (Boxes 5-8; 2.65 linear ft.)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York
Types of Materials:
Visitors' Books; Photographs
Names:
Allain, René Pierre, 1951-; Chaet, Bernard; Freeman, Joseph; Greene, Stephen, 1918-1999; Hill, Clinton, 1922-2003; Lasch, Pat; Loew, Michael, 1907-1985; Lutz, Winifred; McShea, Jim; Miles, Jeanne Patterson, 1908-1999; Pearson, Henry, 1914-; Perez, Pedro; Robin, Stephen, 1944-; Von Wiegand, Charmion; Weiner, Ellen
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Artists' Files, 1925-2000, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-4; 3.6 linear ft.)
  Substantial artist files are found for the following artists, most of whom were represented by Marilyn Pearly Gallery for extended periods: René Pierre Allain, Bernard Chaet, Stephen Greene, Clinton Hill, Pat Lasch, Michael Loew, Winifred Lutz, Jim McShea, Jeanne Miles, Henry Pearson, Stephen Robin, Charmion Wiegand, and Ellen Weiner.
  Artists' files consist, in varying combinations, of correspondence with the artist, collectors, galleries, and museums; printed materials about the artists including publicity, reviews, exhibition catalogs and announcements of Marilyn Pearl Gallery and other venues; photographs, slides, and transparencies of art work, and sometimes of artists or exhibition installations; and financial records concerning sales, exhibition expenses, etc. In general, the items pre- and post-dating the gallery consist of printed material relating to artists. A notable exception is Charmion von Wiegand whose files include personal papers, among them letters from her husband, the writer and editor Joseph Freeman (1897-1965); also found is other personal and professional correspondence, financial and miscellaneous items relating to her travels.
  - Allain, René Pierre, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chaet, Bernard (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Mailing Lists, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Publicity, Reviews, etc., 1951-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1969-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Photograph of the Artist, circa 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Art Work (A-Z by title, unidentified), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Negatives of Art Work (unidentified), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z, by title; unidentified), 1980s-1990s, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Transparencies of Art Work (A-Z by title; untitled), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Greene, Stephen (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Financial Records, 1985-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Lists of Works Available, 1977-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Publicity, Reviews, Biographical Information, etc., 1963-1991, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1961-1992, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - Photographs of the Artist, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Photographs of Art Work (A-Z by title; unidentified), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Negatives of Art Work, circa 1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z, by title; untitled), 1980s, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Transparencies of Art Work (A-Z by title), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hill, Clinton (Box 1)
    - Art Work for Catalog and Poster, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Biographical Notes, circa 1979-circa 1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - Financial Records-Expenses, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Financial Records-Sales and Consignments, 1982-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Notes and Lists, 1990, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Printed Material-Articles and Publicity, 1978-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1969-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Text of Slide Talk, "Materials and Methods in the Prints and Paintings of Clinton Hill," unsigned, circa 1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Photographs of the Artist, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Photographs of Art Work (A-Z, by title; untitled), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Photographs of Art Work (unidentified), undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Negatives of Art Work (unidentified), undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z, by title; untitled; unidentified), undated, (2 slide boxes) (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Slides of Art Work (unidentified), 1981-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Slides of Exhibition Installations, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Transparencies of Art Work, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Lasch, Pat (Box 2)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material-Articles, 1977-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Announcements, 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Photographs of Art Work, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Negative of Art Work, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Slides of Art Work, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Loew, Michael (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Financial Records-Sales and Expenses, 1984-1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Inventory and Appraisal, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Landau Fine Arts-Sales, Consignments, and Exhibition, 1989-1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Legal, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Reviews, Publicity, 1938-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1949-1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Recording, Michael Loew interviewed by Karl Fortess, 1971, (1 sound tape reel) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Writings on Loew, 1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Mormoris, Stephen P. "The Changing Role of Geometry in Michael Loew's Latest Works on Exhibit at the Marilyn Pearl Gallery in New York" (student paper)
      Unsigned. "Michael Loew - Light and Space"
    - Photographs of the Artist, circa 1925-1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Photographs of Home and Studio (Monhegan Island, Maine), 1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Photographs of Art Work (A-Y, by title; untitled), undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Photographs of Art Work (unidentified), undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
    - Photographs of Art Work by Other Artists, 1930, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Jensen, Alfred (portrait of Loew)
      Loew, Jonathan
      unsigned
    - Negative of Michael Loew and Willem de Kooning, 1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Negatives of Art Work, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Men of Coal and Steel, Post Office Mural, Belle Vernon, PA
      Voluminosities
    - Negatives of Art Work (unidentified), circa 1950s-1960s, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z, by title), undated, (slide box) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Slides of Art Work (untitled), undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Slides of Art Work by Other Artists, 1973, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
      de Kooning, Willem [owned by Loew]
    - Slides of Exhibition Installations; Home and Studio (Monhegan Island, Maine), 1965-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Transparencies (A-Z, by title; untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lutz, Winifred (Box 3)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Publicity, Reviews, 1977-1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Photograph Album, "Site-Integrated Sculpture Installations," circa 1984, (disbound volume) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Photographs of Art Work, 1986-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Slides of Art Work, (A-W, by title; untitled; unidentified), undated, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
    - Slides of Art Work, (I-SL, by title), undated, (slide box) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Slides of Art Work (SO-W, by title; untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Transparency of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Video Recordings, undated, (2 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 3, Folder 15)
      "AGO/ANON: An Installation by Winifred Lutz, Brooklyn Museum"
      "A Room for Pause," Western College Alumnae Association, undated
  - McShea, Jim (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1991, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Printed Material, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Slides of Art Work (untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miles, Jeanne (Box 3)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence-Artist, 1986-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence-Clients, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Reviews, Reproductions, 1941-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1960-1989, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - Photographs of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Slide and Transparency of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Pearson, Henry (Box 3)
    - Accounting, 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1983-circa 1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence-Clients, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence-Columbia Museum Show, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Inventory, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Publicity, Reviews, Reproductions, 1966-1991, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1969-1988 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Photograph of the Artist, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Photographs of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Negatives of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z; untitled), undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Transparencies of Art Work (A-Z; unidentified), undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Perez, Pedro, 1985-1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Robin, Stephen (Box 3)
    - Artist's Statement (re: The Garden Series), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1986-1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Printed Material, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Photographs of Exhibition Installation, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Photographs of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Negatives of Art Work, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - von Wiegand, Charmion (Box 4)
    - Accounting, 1975-1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1952-circa 1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Consignments and Consignment Releases, 1978-1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence-Artist, 1963-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence-Bass Museum of Art Exhibition, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence-Clients, Researchers, etc., 1980-2000, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence-Hanson, William R. (attorney), 1982-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Corresponence-Loans, 1979-1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Interview Transcript (Charmion von Wiegand interview with Paul Cummings for Archives of American Art), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Inventories, 1979-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Mailing Lists, 1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Personal Papers-Correspondence, 1941-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Personal Papers-Notes and Writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Personal Papers-Printed Material, 1948-1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Personal Papers-Travel, 1957-1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Printed Material-Article by Charmion von Wiegand ("Mondrian: A Memoir of his New York Period"), undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Printed Material-Articles, Publicity, Reviews, Reproduction, 1958-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Printed Material-Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, Publicity, 1974-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Printed Material - Interview Transcripts (Charmion von Wiegand interviews with Patricia Tate and M.R.), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Writings about Charmion von Wiegand (includes poem by Hsien Liang Koo), 1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Writings about Charmion von Wiegand, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Writings by Charmion von Wiegand, 1941, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Photographs of Artist, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Photographs of Art Work, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Photographs of Exhibition Installation (unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z by title; untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Transparencies of Art Work (A-Z by title; untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Weiner, Ellen (Box 4)
    - Biographical Information, circa 1988 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Consignments, Loans, and Releases, 1985-1998 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Mailing Lists, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Printed Material, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Photographs of Art Work (untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Negatives of Art Work (unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Slides of Art Work (A-Z; untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Transparencies of Art Work (Solid Yellow Blocks; untitled; unidentified), undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Exhibition Files, 1973-1992, Series 2:; (Boxes 4-5; 1.15 linear ft.)
  Exhibition files are arranged chronologically by exhibition date, 1977, 1980-1992. They may include: correspondence with artists, lenders, printers and designers; invoices, insurance policies, and other financial records; printed material including exhibition catalogs, announcements and invitations, publicity, and reviews; photographs, slides, and transparencies of art work, and occasionally of exhibition installations and openings. Materials dated long before or after the run of the exhibition are usually printed items. Group show participants are noted following the folder title.
  - American Geometric Abstract Painting of the 1950s (October 4-29, 1977), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Ilya Bolotowsky
    Burgoyne Diller
    Adolph Fleishcmann
    Fritz Glarner
    Michael Loew
    Alice Trumbull-Mason
    Jeanne Miles
    George L. K. Morris
    Henry Pearson
    Leon Polk Smith
    Albert Swinden
    Charmion von Wiegand
  - Stephen Greene: Recent Paintings (January 5-February 2, 1980), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Henry Pearson: "The Black Rectangle" (February 5-March 1, 1980), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Geometric Tradition in American Painting: 1920-1980 (April 8-May 17, 1980), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Color, Surface, and Geometry: American Painting of the 1940s and 1950s (June 3-July 3, 1981), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Josef Albers
    Giorgio Cavallon
    Al Held
    Alfred Jensen
    Jan Muller
    Ludwig Sander
  - American Figurative Expressionism (1950-1960) (February 6-March 4, 1982), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Gandy Brodie
    Bernard Chaet
    Willem de Kooning
    Leon Golub
    John Graham
    Stephen Greene
    Grace Hartigan
    Lester Johnson
    Alex Katz
    Nathan Oliveira
    Larry Rivers
  - Bernard Chaet and American Master Watercolor Show (October 1982), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Clinton Hill: Paintings and Paper Works (January 11-February 5, 1983), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Paintings of the Fifties (September 6-17, 1983), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    James Brooks
    Byron Brown
    Clinton Hill
    Hans Hofmann
    Franz Kline
    Lee Krasner
    Dody Muller
    Leo Rabkin
    Ad Reinhardt
    Mark Rothko
    Charmion von Weigand
  - Henry Pearson: Recent Paintings (September 20-October 15 1983), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - George Constant: Paintings and Watercolors, 1916- 1945 (October 18-November 12, 1983), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Stephen Greene: "Gardens of the Night" (November 15-December 10, 1983), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Paradise Lost (December 13, 1983-January 7, 1984), 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    Luis Cruz Azaceta
    Rafael Ferrer
    Roberto Juarez
    Pedro Perez
  - Winifred Lutz: A Twist of Fate/Nature Walks (January 10-February 4, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Bernard Chaet: Recent Paintings and Watercolors (February 7-March 3, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Clinton Hill: Paintings, Paperworks, Constructions (March 6-31, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Michael Loew: Recent Paintings and Drawings (April 3-29, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Barbara Siegel: Ornithology: Paintings and Drawings (May 1-29, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    Richard Anuszkiewicz
    Ralston Crawford
    Max Cole
    Nassos Daphnis
    Adolf Fleishman
    Jeremy Gillbert-Rolfe
    Budd Hopkins
    Ellsworth Kelly
    Sol Lewitt
    Robert Mangold
    Agnes Martin
    John McLaughlin
    Frank Stella
    Myron Stout
    George Sugarman
  - American Post War Purism (May 31-September 8, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Leo Rabkin: Boxes and Pastels (September 11-October 6, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Matt Phillips: "Fragments" (October 9-November 3, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Richard Lytle: Recent Paintings and Watercolors (November 6-December 1, 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Inspirit (December 1984), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    Norris Embry
    Peter Flaccus
    Dale Frank
    Andre Masson
    George McNeil
    Sam Messer
    Joan Mitchell
    Garry Nichols
    Joyce Pensato
    Jackson Pollock
    Joel Shapiro
    Chaim Soutine
  - Plastics!? and Linda Peer: Sculpture (December 4, 1984-January 5, 1985), 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    Bill Beckley
    Konrad Cramer
    Porfirio di Donna
    Jasper Johns
    William King
    Robert Morris
    Alfonso Ossorio
    Judy Pfaff
    Richard Pousette-Dart
    Robert Rauschenberg
  - Budd Hopkins: New Work (January 8-February 5, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Between Abstraction and Reality (February 6-March 2, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    Gregory Amenoff
    Anna Bialobroda
    Arthur G. Dove
    Lawrence Fane
    Nancy Graves
    Marsden Hartley
    Bill Jensen
    Georgia O'Keeffe
    Katherine Porter
  - Lawrence Fane: New Work (March 5-30, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Pedro Perez: Paradise Punch (April 3-27, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Charmion von Wiegand (1896-1983): Retrospective Exhibition, 1945-1965 (May 1-June 1, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - New Talent (Parts I and II) (June 4-September 13, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    Josephine Bentivigna
    Peter Dedek
    Julie Heffernen
    James Hennessey
    Andrew Lyndon
    Joseph Militello
    Deborah Muirhea
    Nila Rusnell
    Charles Spurrier
    Ellen Weiner
  - Kitty Klaidman: Before the Sandstorm (September 18-October 12, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Winifred Lutz, New Work (October 16-November 9, 1985), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Stephen Greene: Paintings (November 12-December 7, 1985),1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - The Severe and the Romantic: Geometric Humanism in American Painting, 1950s-1980s (December 10, 1985-January 4, 1986), 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    Richard Diebenkorn
    Heidi Gluck
    Ron Janowich
    Greg Mahoney
    Doug Sanderson
    Stephen Westfall